Michael Pohoreski

6673 NE Wellsly Place, Bremerton, WA 98311 (310) 525-9831, michaelpohoreski@gmail.com

I have 13+ years of programming in the video game industry having shipped 10 games on the following platforms: PC, PlayStation 1 & 2, Nintendo DS, Apple 2, and Wii; additionally I have worked on the PS3, PSP, Vita, and Xbox360 platforms. My roles have included Technical Lead, Engine, Gameplay, and Tools programmer.

I am passionate about graphics, optimization, User Interface, frame rate, and Data-Orientated Design.

I would love to bring my skills to your company!

Technical Skills

Specialties

Graphics, optimization, UI/UX design & implementation

Languages/APIs C++, GLSL, JavaScript, C, OpenGL & ES, WebGL, Win32, OpenMP, CUDA

Apps & Tools Git, VisualStudio, Vim, Photoshop, Blender, Substance Painter

Work Experience

2019-2022 **Senior Graphics Programmer**, Linden Research Inc. (Second Life)

- Implemented Physically Based Rendering (PBR) with IBL (Image Based Lighting),
- Performance analysis integrating RAD Game Tools' *Telemetry* then *Tracy* profiler,
- Maintained and fixed legacy OpenGL rendering code base, and
- Worked with 3rd party developers to submit and merge patches back upstream to SL.

2011-2019 **Senior UI Developer,** Comcast

- Worked on Xfinity Stream Beta App for SmartTVs, Tablets, STBs in JavaScript.
- Next generation UI engine which involved researching, designing and implementing:
 - WebGL 1.x rendering pipeline to augment DOM, easing animation system (21 dimensions, Signed Distance Field font rendering and texture atlas.
 - C++ OpenGL ES rendering engine for embedded Broadcom 742x systems.
- Wrote JavaScript minification C++ toolchain and debugged minified code.
- Logged telemetry using Localytics, Splunk and internal backend systems.
- Ran Splunk queries and did analysis of logs.
- Communicated with team about git, git bisect, history of graphics, and telemetry.
- Helped colleagues with Xbox 360 streaming app. in C#; ported to PS3.

2009-2011 Senior Software Engineer, Sony Computer Entertainment of America

 Analyzed code and assembly, fixed bugs, and added features to PS3, Vita and PSP C++ compilers for developers. Presented road map of tools and debugger usage to game developers. Ported *Bullet* (open source physics library) to PSP.

2008-2009 **Senior Software Engineer**, Majesco Studios

 Developed C++ in-house game engine for Nintendo DS including UI, font rendering, savegame; optimal palette usage; wrote conversion tools; scripting of version control for assets, build system for multiple SKUs.

Michael Pohoreski

2006-2008 Senior Software Engineer, Papaya Studios

- C++ Wii in-house game engine architecture and implementation for CPU and GPU:
 - Ported PS2 game engine to Wii; CPU profiling, vector & matrix optimizations.
 - Implemented subset of OpenGL, GPU profiling, full frame VFX, projected shadows, movie shaders, full frame and per object glow (bloom), implemented 8-bit palettized textures with 32-bit CLUT using 4 TEV stages, optimized 2-bone skinning, dynamic lighting using *Havok* physics middleware, swizzled textures.
- C++ PS2 rendering fixes, per object glow, VU and GS analysis, 4-bone skinning.

2003-2006 Independent Computer Consultant

Produced catalog using InDesign and Photoshop; purchasing advice for hardware.

1999-2003 **Senior Software Engineer**, Cyberlore Studios

- C++ PS2 development of in-house rendering engine before using "RenderWare".
 - Implemented projected texture shadows using "RenderWare" middleware.
 - Integrated "Multistream" middleware sound and streaming library.
 - Optimizations: CDROM/DVD loading into EE memory, movie memory usage.
 - Gamepad, memory card, and timer support.
- Implemented Particle Systems, math optimizations for vectors, matrices, and quaternions.
- Random Number Generator conformance.
- Extended in-house scripting language to control 3D units and camera for cutscenes.
- Wrote a PC renderer engine using D3D8 replacing SurRender D3D5 middleware.

1997-1998 Senior Software Engineer, Appleton Industrial Software

• Designed & implemented Real-Time handwriting recognition in C++ for WinNT 4.0.

1996-1997 **Teaching Assistant**, Simon Fraser University

- CMPT 001: Computers and the Activity of People.
- CMPT 098: Computers, Applications and Programs; graded final exams.

1995-1996 **Junior Software Engineer**, Electronic Arts Canada

• Implemented UI, profiling, memory usage & crash analysis, profiling, and memory card support on *Need For Speed* (PS1).

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computing Science, 1997

Simon Fraser University, Burnaby, BC, Canada

Personal Projects

- WebGL shaders at https://www.shadertoy.com/user/MichaelPohoreski including:
 - HOWTO: Ray Marching, Font: Bitmap vs SDF, etc.
- Buddhabrot OpenMP (done) and CUDA (Work-in-Progress)
- World's smallest 3x4 readable font at https://github.com/Michaelangel007/nanofont3x4
- AppleWin Open source Windows Apple //e emulator (Debugger & Video)